<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miner</title>
    <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Miner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2016, LigniteTech; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 13:01:15 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http:///www.lignitetech.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Compliance</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/financial-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 13:01:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/financial-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Financial Compliance&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Analytics</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/trade-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 13:01:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/trade-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trade Analytics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-miner&#34;&gt;WHAT IS MINER?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LigniteTech Miner is Cloud SaaS is the SaaS (Software as a Service) implementation of a data relationship analysis platform. It aims to provide a mechanism to link and visualize unstructurally related data. There is out of the box support for a variety of publicly available datasources and a flexible data model allows for the easy integration of any proprietary datasource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-graph-database&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A GRAPH DATABASE?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graph databases, like relational databases (RDBMS such as MySQL or PostgreSQL) are used to store and retrieve data. To operate efficiently RDBMSs require that your data is kept in a well known and managed structure. However the increasing complexity of data, the exponential growth of the volume of data generated (generated by automated and manual means) and the dynamic nature and interdependecy of datasources such as social networks mean that using a relational database to model data and it&amp;rsquo;s relationships is increasingly complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take your movie collection. Each movie has &lt;em&gt;metadata&lt;/em&gt;, which is data about the data. The metadata associated with the movie could include the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year released&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie can be thought of as a &lt;em&gt;node&lt;/em&gt;. That is a self contained unit of information. It would be trivial in an RDBMS to create a list of movies that were made in the 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what if you also wanted to model Songs. You could build up a database of songs with it&amp;rsquo;s own associated set of data. So far no problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if it turned out that some of the actors in your movies database are also recording artists. You could model this relationship in a relational database but you would have to have anticipated the relationship before you would be able to run a search along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Find me the actors who starred in a chinese language file in 2009 that also released an album of christmas songs between 2011 and 2013&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about introducing car ownership into the mix. What if you wanted to correlate the results of the previous search with anyone that owns a red car manufactured within the last two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a relational model the greater the complexity of the search, the poorer the performance and the greater the requirement for resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key difference between Relational and Graph is that graph offers the use of metadata for all of its objects and it&amp;rsquo;s all quickly and efficiently available to the databases system to query. The relationships in the data can be dynamically defined and queried. One key thing to note is that graph operations are exectued with constant speed independent of total size of the graph. There are no set operations involved that decrease performance as seen with join operations in an RDBMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-types-of-data-can-be-analysed&#34;&gt;WHAT TYPES OF DATA CAN BE ANALYSED?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any data that can be captured digitally is a candidate for being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance you can see that two people have a connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/person-to-person.png&#34; alt=&#34;Person to Person&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case you can see that a person has a connection to a building&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/person-to-building.png&#34; alt=&#34;Person to Building&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the data model not only are the entities treated as first class citizens but so is the type of connection between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-data-sources-can-be-used&#34;&gt;WHAT DATA SOURCES CAN BE USED?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any addressable source that has a text based data or meta data component can be used as a source. Publicly available streaming sources such as Twitter, Google Plus or Facebook can be used to provide real time data. In addition, static snapshots of data can be provided using Relational databases, NoSQL databases and Flat files. Finally data can also be extracted from Big Data endpoints such as Apache Sparl, Apache Kafka or Apache Flink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-much-data-can-be-analysed&#34;&gt;HOW MUCH DATA CAN BE ANALYSED?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying technology used can be used to efficiently store and retrieve billions of data points. Several hundred thousand events per hour can be consumed, analysed and linked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-proprietary-data-sources-be-used&#34;&gt;CAN PROPRIETARY DATA SOURCES BE USED?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the modular way in which the data is stored, the platform is agnostic about the source of the data. If you require data from a non public source then our consulting team will be available to manage the entire delivery from determining requirements, development, installation and support of the bespoke components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-system-accessed&#34;&gt;HOW IS THE SYSTEM ACCESSED&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically platform is hosted in UK / US / EU data centres, which customers connect using an encrypted web connection. This will require configuration of any customer firewalls which are in place (led by the customer in conjunction with our support team). Platform instances will not be shared between customers or any other third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical service for 5 users will run on a 10Mb/s web connection. We are able to advise on bandwidth requirements for larger deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the service is deployed through a browser, a low latency connection is not required for the service to operate effectively. Given the nature of the technology in use a modern web browser will be required (eg Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the data being analysed is of a sensitive nature then self hosted options are available and will require a custom price plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need further information please feel free to contact us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard Driven</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A personalised dashboard view for each user. A reactive dashboard screen that gives the user an at a glance overview of the system, any updates to worksets and any active alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/miner-dashboard.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Events&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law Enforcement Support</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/law-enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/law-enforcement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Law Enforcement Support&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Generation</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/lead-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/lead-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lead Generation&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reputation Analysis</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/reputation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reputation Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/safety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Safety&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fraud detection</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fraud Detection&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Analysis</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/link-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:01:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/solution/link-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Link Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative Worksets</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/collab-workset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 22:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/collab-workset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Share investigations between teams, comment on any piece of data, set up real time alerts for when data changes and export to external systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/workset-overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;Collaborative Worksets&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can carry out investigations on a specific groups of data. A dashboard view provides an overview of all their current worksets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workset Summary</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/workset-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/workset-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workset Summary. A responsive system overview customised for each user&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/workset-summary.png&#34; alt=&#34;Workset Summary&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network view of data</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/workset-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/workset-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Network view of workset data. See how the entities in a workset are related. Increase the depth of the relationships to discover patterns and relationship clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/workset-network.png&#34; alt=&#34;Collaborative Workset Network View&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location aware data view</title>
      <link>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/workset-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:///www.lignitetech.com/item/workset-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workset Location view. Any entity with GeoLocation information, will be displayed on the map. The map instantly reflects any incoming data with location information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http:/www.lignitetech.com/img/screenshots/workset-location.png&#34; alt=&#34;Collaborative Workset Location View&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>